five and then the Texans of course with
Keelen Rutled as we just mentioned out
of Georgia Tech. Back with Fach
Lombardi, Brian Bratis, Zack Walchuk,
Tommy Yarish, I'm Kyleman's now joined
by the newest Dallas Cowboy, Malachi
Lawrence, edge rusher from UCF is on the
line. Malachi, congratulations. What was
that moment like getting the phone call
from Jerry Jones in the Cowboys front
office?
>> Uh, it was amazing. Uh, it was like
first things all glory to God. But it
was it was a blessing and a dream come
true. Been playing football since I was
five and always wanted to play in the
NFL. So, like I said, it was an amaz
It's something I can't even explain.
>> No doubt about it. I'm going to ask you
to explain it a little bit. Malachi, you
you stayed there at UCF. You you
finished top 10 in terms of their career
sack leaders and you're one of the best
players in program history. What does it
mean to you and your family to now have
the the first round tag next to your
name and get to live out that dream now
here in Dallas?
>> Right. Like I said, it's a blessing. Uh
a dream come true. Like you said, um I'm
just ready to come in and work. Like
like you said, that first round tag,
like at the beginning of this year, I
just didn't even I couldn't dream of it.
But like just the work that I put in
like like I said all glory to God and
I'm just proud of myself and thankful
for the people that helped me along the
way.
>> Malachi, congratulations, man. Welcome
to the Dallas Cowboys. We can't wait to
have you here. What's the relationship
like with you and Coach Brim, who's also
now on staff here in Dallas and how much
did that maybe help during this process?
>> Right. Uh my relationship with Coach
Brim is great. I think it helped
definitely a lot. Um, like I said, we
were at UCF together. He helped us a lot
with film work, uh, as well as on the
field, just giving us little tips and
then like just having those one-on-one
talks with him was just a great thing to
have. And then just being able to have
him in Dallas now, that's just, like I
said, it's a great thing to have him.
>> Malachi, welcome, welcome, welcome. you
know, just watching your film, you know,
some guys rush with a pass rush plan and
then, you know, surely you do too, but
just watching you, it seems like you
pass rush more on feel, like something
happens and you just kind of react to
it. Uh, you know, break down break down
how do you pass rush and put different
rush moves together,
>> right? Um, like you said, it kind of
comes off feel and also like just game
plan and watching film and like I
believe that I have a good repertoire of
moves that I can work and so just going
up against those tackles. Some some
weeks I can't use the same moves as I
could other weeks on different on
another tackle. So it's just like having
those moves also in my bag just in case
a tackle gives me a different set and a
different look.
>> That's hard. Yeah, good stuff. Malachi
Lawrence joining us here on the Dallas
Cowboys Radio Network. The 23rd overall
pick in this year's NFL draft. Tommy,
you have something for Malachi?
>> Yeah, Malachi. Hey, congratulations,
man. Uh kind of tell Cowboys fans out
there that are listening what what kind
of player and person are they getting
here in in Malachi Lawrence?
>> Right. They're getting a a relentless
player, someone that's just ready to
come in and work. um a relentless motor
like I'm just going to chase that ball
no matter what. And then as a person
getting a great person, someone who's
going to bring a great a great face and
uh like have the Cowboys name in good
hands.
>> No doubt about it. Tell us about a
little bit of your background. Who
inspired you early in your career and
who are some of the players maybe in the
NFL now that you've modeled your game
after as you continue to grow uh and get
to the next level?
>> Right. Um, coming into UTF, um, uh, uh,
the edge rusher named Trayon Morris
Brash, we called him drop. Uh, I'd say
he definitely inspired me just how he
practiced and the moves he would use at
practice and then like I would kind of
replicate those and then I would do them
in my own little craft or my own little
way. So I say him and then um, what was
the other question?
>> Yeah. NFL players, anybody that you
model your game after,
>> right? Yeah. I like to watch Chandler
Jones, Will Anderson, um Denil Hunter. I
like those guys. They're different,
unorthodox, and they know how to use
their their strengths.
>> Have you talked with Christian Parker at
all about how your usage will be uh in
this defense moving forward throughout
the process,
>> right? Yeah. Um yeah, we talked a little
bit about it like I'm I'm gonna be that
edge edge defender, edge rusher, getting
to the quarterback, ready to play the
run, ready to be stopped in. So, yes,
sir. We talk about that.
>> Awesome stuff. Malachi Lawrence, Ed
Rusher from UCF and the newest Dallas
Cowboys joining us on the phone line.
Malachi getting it. Congratulations. Go
celebrate with your family. Can't wait
to talk to you tomorrow.
>> Yes, sir. Thank you so much.
>> There he goes. Malachi Lawrence. Awesome
stuff. Excited to see him.
>> Let me just say people that Shotti's
been drafting like they've all been like
good dudes. We going to work hard. We
all leadership. We all locked in. Like
they all sound the same. like all those
I don't want I don't want to say the
right kind of